Do you know the names of the people who live next door?
你知道隔壁邻居的名字吗？
Chances are you live next to someone, but do you actually know them?
你大概率有邻居，但你真的了解他们吗？
Sadly, the only time we do seem to hear about people’s neighbours is when things go wrong – hearing people say things like they have the neighbours from hell!
遗憾的是，我们似乎只有在邻里关系出问题的时候，才会听到人们谈论邻居——比如常听到有人抱怨自己遇上了“极品邻居”！
So, what does go wrong?
那么，究竟是哪些问题会引发邻里矛盾呢？
When talking about famous feuds with people who live in proximity, you only need to think of the Montagues and Capulets in Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.
说到著名的邻里宿怨，你只需要想想莎士比亚《罗密欧与朱丽叶》中的蒙太古家族和凯普莱特家族就够了。
Thankfully, most real-life quarrels don’t go that far.
幸好，现实生活中的大多数邻里争吵都不会闹到那么过分。
These days, especially in cities, many people live in condominiums, tightly packed into apartment blocks.
如今，尤其是在城市里，许多人住在格局紧凑的公寓楼里。
Our neighbours are all around us – so what issues can come from that?
邻居们近在咫尺——那么，这种居住环境会引发哪些问题呢？
The first obvious cause of dispute is noise pollution.
引发邻里纠纷的第一个显而易见的原因是噪音污染。
Loud bass pumping through the walls, construction, or people arguing next door can disrupt the harmony of your living space.
穿墙而来的强劲低音、施工的嘈杂声、或是隔壁邻居的争吵声，都可能破坏你居住空间的和谐氛围。
Asking someone directly to turn the music down can cause you to feel anxious.
直接要求对方把音乐声调小，可能会让你感到紧张不安。
However, getting someone like a building manager involved to speak to your neighbour and making complaints official can make things more awkward down the line as you didn’t speak to your neighbour directly.
但如果让物业经理这类人出面沟通，或是正式投诉，又会因为你没有直接和邻居交涉，而让后续的邻里相处变得更加尴尬。
And then what about smells?
还有气味问题。
If your neighbour likes eating especially pungent food, something that offends your nostrils, and that smell drifts through your window, what can you do?
如果你的邻居喜欢吃气味特别浓烈、让你难以忍受的食物，而且这些味道飘进了你的窗户，你该怎么办？
Some other common issues include water leaking through the ceiling, pets making noise, and littering from the balcony above you.
其他常见的邻里问题还包括天花板漏水、宠物吵闹、以及楼上邻居从阳台往下乱扔垃圾。
And then, if you’re lucky enough to own a garden, that can present even more issues to fight with your neighbour about!
如果你足够幸运，拥有一片自家花园，那可能会引发更多和邻居争吵的问题！
This could include hedges and fences that are too high, balls and toys invading your garden or hitting your windows, and boundary disputes over where your neighbours’ land ends.
比如邻居家的树篱或围栏过高、球和玩具掉进你家花园甚至砸到窗户、以及关于邻里地界划分的纠纷。
All these can create animosity over time.
久而久之，这些问题都会滋生邻里间的敌意。
It’s not easy living next door to someone, especially if they’re noisy.
和别人做邻居并非易事，尤其是当对方很吵闹的时候。
But having a clear and honest line of dialogue might help.
但保持清晰坦诚的沟通或许能起到作用。
Also, try considering if the things you are doing could upset your neighbours.
此外，不妨换位思考一下，自己的所作所为是否会打扰到邻居。
If it’s something that would upset you, maybe think again.
如果换作是你，也会为此感到不快，那或许就该三思而后行了。